<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Debjoy&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drone Racing Optimisation</title>
      <link>/project/flipkart-grid2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/flipkart-grid2.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Team Drone-Acharya in the Finals!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worked as a part of Drone-Acharya Team, IIT Kharagpur for the Flipkart GRID-2.0 Robotics Track Competition: Autonomous Indoor Drone. Working on an Imitation-Learning based learning algorithm for fast Quadrotor trajectory planning using DAGGER. Fully deployed an expert minimum-snap trajectory generation algorithm on Microsoft AirSim Simulator on a custom warehouse environment built on Unreal Engine.
More details coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hateful Memes Detection</title>
      <link>/project/hatememe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/hatememe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Performed Pretraining and Finetuning of cutting-edge Multimodal Attention-based models like Visual-BERT and Concat-BERT. Experimented with different dataset augmentations and training techniques like negative supervision. Paper coming soon!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently ranked 18th in the leaderboard for the Hatememe detection Challenge, NIPS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warehouse management using Quadrotors</title>
      <link>/project/imav/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/imav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed a algorithm for autonomous warehouse inventory management using UAVs for the 11th International Micro Aerial Vehicles competition and conference(IMAV-2019). Devised a traversal algorithm using coloured frames for localisation, for performing the complete inventory in minimum time on a DJI-Tello
microdrone. Developed the OCR tools for accurate detection of alphanumeric codes using google’s Tesseract library and QR-codes using Zbar library for inventory management of boxes in a warehouse. Won the IMAV-2019 Indoor Competition! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
